Guide to the Hanna Rustow European travel slides and negatives, 1932-1975 and undated RL.11293
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hanna Rustow European travel slides and negatives
1932-1975 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
Rustow, Hanna
RL.11293
1.5 Linear Feet 3 boxes 471 items
Collection of color slides and black-and-white negatives with images taken by an unidentified photographer during travels in Europe and the United States, with a focus on cities and historical sites in Greece, London, Paris, and Italy. Almost all the slides are of landscapes or tourist sites, but there are a few images with people in them. The black-and-white nitrate negatives contain many images of individuals, both adults and children, perhaps family members, chiefly taken in the United States in the 1930s; there are also shots taken in Florence, Torcello, and Venice, Italy. Original captions are in German.
Content Description
Collection chiefly comprises color slides with images taken by an unidentified photographer during travels in Europe chiefly in the 1960s, with a focus on cities and historical sites in Greece such as Athens, Sparta, Mystras, Meteora, and Perachora. There are also many shots of Portovenere (Italy), and some images taken in London, Switzerland, and Paris. Almost all the slides are of landscapes or tourist sites, but there are a few with people in them. One series is from a helicopter ride over an unidentified European locality. There are also several slides of art work photographed during museums visits.
Also included in the collection are 68 black-and-white nitrate negative strips and frames containing many informal shots of adults and children, perhaps family members, chiefly taken in the United States in the 1930s. Among the negatives are also images taken in Florence, Torcello, and Venice. One shot appears to have been taken in North Carolina, possibly at Duke University.
German captions were taken from original folders. Access to original negatives requires permission of Rubenstein curator.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Hanna Rustow European travel slides and negatives were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 2009.
Tourism -- Europe; Greece -- Photographs; London (England) -- Photographs; Italy -- Photographs; Paris (France) -- Photographs; United States -- Photographs; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University)
- Slides, 1954-1975 and undated; 403 items
  Scope and Contents
  These color slides consist mainly of images taken in Greece and Portovenere (Italy) chiefly during the 1960s, with a few from Paris, London, and Switzerland. Titles were transcribed from German handwriting on original boxes.
  One slide in "Miscellaneous" folder has "Processed by Nelson Studio, Durham" stamped on slide mount, and is labeled in pencil, "Wilson window"; it shows an interior with lamp and window. It is possibly from a building at Duke University.
  - Andritsena-Pyrgos, 1961, 10 items (Box 1)
  - Athen, 1961, 1966, 11 items (Box 1)
  - Bassae, 1961, 6 items (Box 1)
  - Brallos, 1961, 7 items (Box 1)
  - Donan/Wun [Donan Castle?], undated, 44 items (Box 1)
  - Eretina, Kalabaka, Pyros, 1961, and Sanibel, Florida, 1974, 45 items (Box 1)
  - Esel [donkey], 1961, 6 items (Box 1)
  - Flug (Helicopter), 1960, 12 items (Box 1)
  - Gaffron, 1975, 21 items (Box 1)
  - Kaistriani, 1966, 11 items (Box 1)
  - Klar Limne [Limnes, Greece], undated, 20 items (Box 1)
  - Levadia, 1961, 8 items (Box 1)
  - London, 1960, 8 items (Box 1)
  - Mallia, 1966, 6 items (Box 2)
  - Meteora, 1961, 15 items (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous views, 1954, undated, 17 items (Box 2)
  - Mistra, Sparta, 1961, 22 items (Box 2)
  - National Gallery, 2 items (Box 2)
  - Perachora (Loutraki), 1961, 5 items (Box 2)
  - Portovenen [Portovenere, Italy], undated, 61 items (Box 2)
  - Schweiz, 1960, 30 items (Box 2)
  - Zuger See, 1960, 36 items (Box 2)
- Negatives, 1932-1937 and undated; 68 items
  Series contains 68 black-and-white nitrate negatives in both 35 and 64 millimeter sizes. Some are cut into smaller strips and individual frames. Subjects seem to be persons and places in the U.S., as well as several series taken in Italy. No positive images are known to exist; for access to these negatives, please contact a Rubenstein Library reference archivist.
  - Amerika, 1932, 16 items (Box 3)
  - Megan Ann, 1937, 7 items (Box 3)
  - Amerika, 1937, 11 items (Box 3)
  - Loeams (?), undated, 1 item (Box 3)
  - Sdiff [ship?], 1937, 4 items (Box 3)
  - Torcello, undated, 3 items (Box 3)
  - Italien a Venedig [Venice], undated, 5 items (Box 3)
  - Florenz, undated, 4 items (Box 3)
  - O.P., N.P. [people's initials], undated, 3 items (Box 3)
  - C.S. [person's initials], undated, 4 items (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous [unidentified subjects], undated, 3 items (Box 3)
  - Dûr [?], undated, 6 items (Box 3)
  - Dŭr personen [?], 1 item (Box 3)